Guide to the Mexican movie posters, ca. 1940-1989
Department of Special Collections
Mexican movie posters,
ca. 1940-1989
M0945
Mario Moreno
12 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection contains 410 Mexican movie posters dating 1940 through the 1980s.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1997.
Provenance
Purchased, 1997.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Moreno, Mario.; Motion pictures--Mexico.; Posters.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Boxes 1-7 contain posters from the 1940s, 1950s, and 1960s arranged alphabetically by name of movie. Boxes 8-14 contain posters from the 1970s and 1980s also arranged alphabetically by name. Posters in map folder are from the full date range; 7 are of the character Cantinflas and drawn by Mario Moreno.
Collection Contents
- MEXCICAN MOVIE POSTERSca. 1940-1969, 28 POSTERS (Box 1)
  - ABISMOS DE PASION
  - ACA LAS TORTAS
  - ADAN Y EVA
  - AGUILA 0 SOL (A)
  - AGUILA 0 SOL (B)
  - AHI VIENEN LOS GORRONES
  - ALBUR DE AMOR
  - AMBICIOSOS, LOS
  - AMOR ABRIO LOS OJOS, EL
  - AMOR EN LA SOMBRA
  - AMOR NO ES NEGOCIO, EL
  - AMOR PERDIDO
  - ANGELITOS NEGROS
  - ANONIMO MORTAL
  - APUROS DE MI AHIJADA, LOS
  - ASESINOS DE LA NOCHE
  - ASESINOS, S.A.
  - AY CHAPARROS COMO
  - ABUNDAN!
  - BAILE MI REY
  - BAJO EL MANTO DE LA NOCHE
  - BAJO LA INFLUENCIA DEL MIEDO
  - BARRIO BAJO
  - BELLA OTERO, LA
  - CAMINOS DE SANGRE
  - CAFE COLON
  - CANTANDO NACE EL AMOR
  - CARITA DE CIELO
  - CARTAS MARCADAS
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERSca. 1940-1969, 31 posters (Box 2)
  - CASA CHICA, LA
  - CASA DE PERDICION
  - CASA DEL TERROR, LA
  - CASADO CASA QUIERE, EL
  - CASTO SUSANO, EL
  - CIEN DIAS DE SAFARI
  - COMICOS DE LA LEGUA
  - CON QUIEN ANDAN NUESTRAS
  - HIJAS
  - CONOZCO A LOS DOS
  - COQUETA
  - CORAZON SAL VAJE
  - CUANDO ME VAYA
  - CUANDO TU ME QUIERAS
  - CUARTO DE HOTEL
  - CUATRO NOCHES CONTIGO
  - CHAMACA, LA
  - CHANOC VS EL TIGRE Y EL VAMPIRO
  - CHARRO DEL ARRABAL, EL
  - CHARRO DEL CRISTO, EL
  - CHIFLADOS DEL ROCK'N ROLL
  - DANCING (SALON DE BAILE)
  - DE CARNE SOMOS
  - DEL RANCHO A LA CAPITAL
  - DERECHO DE NACER, EL
  - DESEO
  - DIOS LOS CRIA
  - DONDE EL CIRCULO TERMINA
  - DONA MARIQUITA DE MI CORAZON
  - DONA PERFECTA
  - DR. SATAN
  - DR. SATAN Y LA MAGIA NEGRA
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERSca. 1940-1969, 30 POSTERS (Box 3)
  - DUDA, LA
  - DUELO EN LAS MONTANAS
  - DUENA Y SENORA
  - DULCE ENEMIGA, LA
  - ENSAYO DE UN CRIMEN
  - ENTRE TU AMOR Y EL CIELO
  - ESCUCHA MI CANCION
  - ESOS DE PENJAMO!
  - ESPOSA 0 AMANTE
  - EUGENIA GRANDET
  - FERIA DE SAN MARCOS, LA
  - FERNANDEZ DE PERALVILLO, LOS
  - FIJATE QUE SUAVE
  - FLOR DE SANGRE
  - FRENTE AL PECADO DE AYER
  - FURIA ROJA
  - GATO SIN BOTAS, EL
  - GITANA BLANCA, LA
  - GRAN CASINO
  - GRITO DE LA MtJERTE, EL
  - HAY UN NINO EN SU FUTURO
  - HECHIZO TRAGICO
  - ILUSION VIAJA EN TRANVIA, LA
  - INCREIBLE PROFESOR ZOVEK, EL
  - INDIANO, EL
  - INTRUSA, LA
  - INVASION DE LOS MUERTOS, LA
  - ISLA DE LOS DINOSAURIOS, LA
  - JOYAS DEL PECADO, LAS
  - KID TABACO
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERSca. 1940-1969, 26 POSTERS (Box 4)
  - LIGA DE LAS MUCHACHAS, LA
  - LOCA, LA
  - LOCURA PASIONAL
  - LOS QUE NO DEBEN NACER
  - LLEVAME EN TUS BRAZOS
  - MALDICION DE LA MOMIA AZTECA, LA
  - MALDITA CIUDAD
  - MALQUERIDA, LA
  - MANZANAS DE DOROTEA, LAS
  - MARIA CANDELARIA
  - MARIA MAGDALENA
  - MARIDO DE MI NOVIA, EL
  - MARIPOSAS NEGRAS
  - MARQUESA DEL BARRIO, LA
  - MARTIR DEL CALVARIO, EL
  - MATERNIDAD IMPOSIBLE
  - ME GUSTAN TODAS
  - MEDICO DE GUARDIA
  - MI ADORADA CLEMENTINA
  - MI NOV10 ES UN SALVAJE
  - MIENTRAS EL CUERPO AGUANTE
  - MIERCOLES DE CENIZA
  - MIS 3 VIUDAS ALEGRES
  - MUERTE EN ESTE JARDIN, LA
  - MUJER AJENA, LA
  - MUJER DECENTE, UNA
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERSca. 1940-1969, 26 POSTERS (Box 5)
  - MUJER QUE YO PERDI, LA
  - MUJER SIN LAGRIMAS, LA
  - MUJERES DEL PARAISO (TEHUANTEPEC)
  - MULATA
  - MUSICA Y DINERO
  - NAZARIN
  - NINO DE LAS MONJAS, EL
  - NINO Y LA NIEBLA, EL
  - NOCHE DE PERDICION
  - NUNCA DEBIERON AMARSE
  - NUNCA ME HAGAN ESO
  - PABLO Y CAROLINA
  - PASION JAROCHA
  - PASIONARIA
  - PENA, PENITA
  - PENON DE LAS ANIMAS, EL
  - PEREGRINA
  - PERLA, LA
  - PIEL CANELA
  - PLAGIARIO, EL
  - PLEBEYO, EL
  - POBRE CORAZON
  - POLICIAS Y LADRONES
  - POMPEYO EL CONQUISTADOR
  - POR QUERER A UNA MUJER
  - POSESION, LA
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERSca. 1940-1969, 27 POSTERS (Box 6)
  - PRECIO DE LA GLORIA, EL
  - PUEBLO, CANTO Y ESPERANZA
  - RADIO PATRULLA
  - RAPTO, EL
  - RAYO DEL SUR, EL
  - RECIEN CASADOS, NO MOLESTAR
  - REFIFI ENTRE LAS MUJERES
  - REGRESO DEL MONSTRUO, EL
  - REINA DEL MAMBO, LA
  - RENCOR DE LA TIERRA, EL
  - RIO Y LA MUERTE, EL
  - RISA DE LA CIUDAD, LA
  - RONDALLA
  - ROSA BLANCA, LA
  - ROSA BLANCA
  - ROSAURO CASTRO
  - SANGRE EN EL BARRIO
  - SANTA CLAUS
  - SANTO CONTRA CAPULINA
  - SANTO VS EL ESTRANGULADOR
  - SANTO VS EL REY DEL CRIMEN
  - SANTO VS LOS CAZADORES DE CABEZAS
  - SANTO. VS LOS VILLANOS DEL RING
  - SANTO Y EL AGUILA REAL
  - SECRETARIA PELIGROSA
  - SEMINARISTA, EL
  - SENDA PROHIBIDA
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1940-1969, 28 POSTERS (Box 7)
  - SENTENCIA
  - SENORA AMA
  - SI ADELITA SE FUERA CON OTRO
  - SIETE LEGUAS, EL
  - SIETE MUJERES
  - SIGNO DE LA MUERTE, EL
  - SIGUEME CORAZON
  - SIMBAD EL MAREADO
  - SIN VENTURA, LA
  - SOL SALE PARA TODOS, EL
  - SOLAMENTE UNA VEZ
  - SOMBRA DEL OTRO, LA
  - SOMBRA VERDE
  - TALPA
  - TE VI EN T.V.
  - TIBURONEROS
  - TRES GARCIA, LOS
  - TU RECUERDO Y YO
  - TU, SOLO TU
  - TU VIDA ENTRE MIS MANOS
  - ULTIMA NOCHE, LA
  - VIAJE A LA LUNA
  - VIEJOS SOMOS ASI, LOS
  - VIVIR A TODO DAR
  - YO MATE A ROSITA ALVIREZ
  - YO NO CREO EN LOS HOMBRES
  - YO SABIA DEMASIADO
  - YO SOY MUY MACHO
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 31 POSTERS (Box 8)
  - A QUE LE TIRAS CUANDO SUENAS
  - ACTO DE POSESION
  - ADORABLE SINVERGUENZA, UN
  - ADORABLES MUJERCITAS, LAS
  - AGENTE VIAJERO, EL
  - AHORCADO, EL
  - ALBURES MEXICANOS
  - AMANTE ANDA SUELTO, UN
  - AMARGURA DE MI RAZA, LA
  - AMOR EXTRANO, UN
  - AMOR LIBRE
  - ANIMA DE SAYULA, EL
  - ANONIMO MORTAL
  - APANDO, EL
  - ANGELA MORANTE
  - ANO DE LA PESTE, EL
  - AVENTURAS IDE UN CABALLO BLANCO
  - AZUL
  - BARRIO DE CAMPEONES
  - BARRIO SALVAJE
  - BLANCA NIEVES Y SUS 7 AMANTES
  - BLANCO, LOROJO Y LO NEGRO, LO
  - CABALGANDO A LA LUNA
  - CABALLITO VOLADOR, EL
  - CABALLO ALAZAN LUCERO
  - CANANEA
  - CAPULINA VS LOS MONSTRUOS
  - CAPULINA VS LOS VAMPIROS
  - CASCABEL
  - CICLON
  - COMO MEXICO NO HAY DOS
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 31 POSTERS (Box 9)
  - COMPLOT MONGOL,, EL
  - CORONACION
  - CRISTO 70
  - CUANDO QUIERO LLORAR NO LLORO
  - CUANDO TEJEN LAS ARANAS
  - 41 EL HOMBRE PERFECTO
  - CUARTELAZO
  - COLOR DE NUESTRA PIEL, EL
  - CRUZ DE OLVIDO
  - COYOTE Y LA BRONCA, EL
  - CRONICA ROJA
  - CHANOC VS EL TIGRE Y EL VAMPIRO
  - CHICANO
  - CHICO RAMOS
  - CHICOASEN
  - CHILE PICANTE
  - DE PULQUERO A MILLONARIO
  - DESEO EN OTONO, EL
  - DIAS DE COMBATE
  - DIOS, EL NINO YEL MAR
  - DISCOTEC FIN DE SEMANA
  - DISCOTECA ES AMOR
  - DISTRITO FEDERAL
  - DONA MACABRA
  - DOS CARNALES, LOS
  - DULCES NAVAJAS
  - EN BUSCA DE UN MURO
  - EN EL PAlS DE LOS PIES LIGEROS
  - ENCUENTRO DE UN HOMBRE SOLO, EL
  - ESOS VIEJOS RABOVERDES
  - EROTICA
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 32 POSTERS (Box 10)
  - EVA Y DARIO
  - FALTAS A LA MORAL
  - FANTASMA DEL LAGO, EL
  - FE, ESPERANZA Y CARIDAD
  - FIERAS CONTRA FIERAS
  - FUERZAS VIVAS, LAS
  - FUEGO DE MI AHIJADA, EL
  - FUERZA INUTIL, LA
  - FUGA DE CARRASCO, LA
  - FURIAS BAJO EL CIELO
  - GALLINA MUY PONEDORA, UNA
  - GEMELOS ALBOROTADOS, LOS
  - GOLFA DEL BARRIO, LA
  - GRAN PERRO MUERTO, EL
  - GUERRA ES UN BUEN NEGOCIO, LA
  - GUERRILLERO DEL NORTE
  - HALLAZ GO SANGRIENTO
  - HAN VIOLADO A UNA MUJER
  - HIJO DE LA CALAVERA, EL
  - HILARIO CORTES, REY DEL TALON
  - HOMBRE DE LA MANDOLINA, EL
  - HOMBRE LLAMADO EL DIABLO, UN
  - HOMBRE DE LOS HONGOS, EL
  - HOMBRES NO LLORAN, LOS
  - IMPONENTE, EL
  - INCREIBLE PROFESOR ZOVEK, EL
  - INDOLENTES, LOS
  - INFIERNO DE TODOS TAN TEMIDO, EL
  - INVESTIGADOR CAPULINA, EL
  - ISLA DE LOS HOMBRES SOLOS, LA
  - ISLA DE RAROTONGA, LA
  - JAPONESES NO ESPERAN, LOS
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 30 POSTERS (Box 11)
  - JARDIN DE TIA ISABEL, EL
  - JESUS, MARIA Y JOSE
  - JESUS NUESTRO SENOR
  - JESUS EL NINO DIOS
  - JUAN PEREZ JOLOTE
  - JUAN CHARRASQUEADO-GABINO BARRERA
  - JUEZ DE LA SOGA, EL
  - JUVENTUD DESNUDA
  - LEYENDA DE AMOR, UNA
  - LEYENDA DE RODRIGO, LA
  - LIO DE FALDAS
  - LONGITUD DE GUERRA
  - LOS DE ABAJO
  - LUCHA CON LA PANTERA, LA
  - LUGAR SIN LIMITES, EL
  - LLAMADA DEL SEXO, LA
  - LLAMENME MIKE
  - LLANTO DE LA TORTUGA, ELLANTO, RISAS Y KNOCK OUT
  - MAMA DE LA NOVIA, LA
  - MAMA SOLITA
  - MAMA, SOY PAQUITO
  - MARIACHI
  - MARIPOSAS DISECADAS, LAS
  - MAS NEGRO QUE LA NOCHE
  - ME CAl DE LA NUBE
  - MESES Y LOS DIAS, LOS
  - MEXICANO, EL
  - MEXICANO, TU PUEDES
  - MEXICO DE MIS AMORES
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 30POSTERS (Box 12)
  - MEXICO DE NOCHE
  - MEXICO 2000
  - MEXICO NORTE
  - MI AVENTURA EN PUERTO RICO
  - MIL CAMINOS TIENE LA MUERTE
  - MUGROSITA, LA
  - MUJER DEL DIABLO, LA
  - MUJER PERFECTA, LA
  - MUNDO MAGICO
  - MUNECA REINA
  - NAUFRAGIO
  - NI MODO, ASI SOMOS
  - NINA DE LA MOCHILA AZUL, LA
  - NINO DEL TAMBOR, EL
  - NINO Y EL TIBURON, EL
  - NO TIENE LA CULPA EL INDIO
  - NOCHES DE CARNAVAL
  - NOCHE DEL KU KLUX KLAN, LA
  - NOCHE VIOLENTA, LA
  - NOCHES DE CABARET
  - NOCHES DE PALOMA, LAS
  - NOCHES DEL BLANQUITA
  - 96 HORAS DE AMOR o
  - NUEVO MUNDO
  - OFICIO DE TINIEBLAS
  - OLIMPIADA EN MEXICO
  - OTRA VIRGINIDAD, LA
  - OYE SALOME
  - PAYBUCIO SANTO
  - PARA USTED, JEFA
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 30 POSTERS (Box 13)
  - PASAJEROS EN TRANS ITO
  - PECADO DE ADAN Y EVA, EL
  - PEOR QUE LOS BUITRES
  - PEQUENO ROBIN HOOD, EL
  - PEQUENOS PRIVILEGIOS, LOS
  - PERROS DE DIOS, LOS
  - PICARDIA MEXICANA
  - PISTOLEROS FAMOSOS
  - PLAZA DE PUERTO SANTO, LA
  - POBRE PERO HONRADA
  - PRESIDENTA MUNICIPAL, LA
  - PRIMER AMOR, EL
  - PRIMER PASO DE LA MUJER, EL
  - PROFETA MIMI, E
  - PULQUERIA, LA
  - PULQUERIA, LA (part 2)
  - PUM
  - QUE BRAVAS SON LAS SOLTERAS
  - RAICES DE SANGRE
  - RECOGIDA, LA
  - REED, MEXICO INSURGENTE
  - REDIEZCUBRIMIENTO DE MEXICO, EL
  - REY DE LOS GORILAS, EL
  - REY DE OROS
  - REY DEL MASAJE, EL
  - RINCON DE LAS VIRGENES, EL
  - RIO DE ORO
  - ROBACHICOS
  - SAN SIMON DE LOS MAGUEYES
  - SANTO OFICIO, EL
- MEXICAN MOVIE POSTERS ca. 1970-1989, 30 POSTERS (Box 14)
  - SENOR DE OSANTO, EL
  - SOLO PARA DAMAS
  - SOR TEQUILA
  - SOY EL HIJO DEL GALLERO
  - SUCESION, LA
  - SUPERSABIOS, LOS
  - TE QUIERO
  - TESTAMENTO, EL
  - TIA ALEJANDRA, LA
  - TIERRA PROMETIDA, LA
  - TIVOLI
  - TONTO QUE HACIA MILAGROS, EL
  - TORITO DE TEPITO, EL
  - TRES MUJERES EN LA HOGUERA
  - TRINQUETERO, EL
  - TUERTO ANGUSTIAS, EL
  - ULTRAJE
  - VACACIONES MISTERIOSAS
  - VERANO ARDIENTE
  - VIBORA CALIENTE
  - VICTORIA
  - VIDA INUTIL DE PITO PEREZ, LA
  - VIDITA NEGRA
  - VIVA EL CHUBASCO
  - VIVIR PARA AMAR
  - XOXONTLA, TIERRA QUE ARDE
  - YA SE QUIEN ERES, TE HE ESTADO OBSERVADO
  - YESENIA
  - ZINDY, EL NINO DE LOS PANTANOS
  - ZORRO BLANCO, EL
- Mexican Movie Posters (Map-case 1)
  - Santo en las bestias del terror
  - Las fuerzas vivas
  - Zona roja
  - Cosa facil
  - Adriana del Rio, Actriz
  - En Ia trampa
  - Los albaniles
  - La coquito
  - La casa del pelicano
  - Yo fui violada
  - Mictian
  - Noche de muerte
  - Santo frente a la muerte
  - Santo contra el doctor muerte
  - El castillo de las momias de guanajuato
  - Santo vs. La majia negra
  - Santo v las lobas
  - La mujer murcielago (Bat-woman)
  - Santo en el museo de cora
  - Santo vs. Las mujeres vampiro
  - El mundo de los vampiros
  - Lujuria de marihuana
  - Blue Demon
  - La generala
  - Los invisibles
  - Manos arriba
  - Tin-Tan en las Tijera de oro
  - Cantinflas: Romeo y Julieta
  - Cantinflas: Los tres mosqueteros
  - Cantinflas: El gendarme desconocido
  - Cantinflas: El supersabio
  - Cantinflas: A volarjoven
  - Cantinflas: El bombero atomicl
  - Cantinflas: Ni sangre ni arena